(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.2",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
生まれたてのドキドキを響かせよう
Let the newborn heart-throb resound
最高の時間 最高の仲間と
The best time with the best friends
キラメキにのって Yeah!
Ride on the sparkle, Yeah!
みんな、今日は来てくれてありがとう。楽しんでいってね！
Everyone, thank you for coming today. Please enjoy yourself!
覚えてるかな？最初の歌
Do you remember? My first song
私 声が震えていた
My voice was trembling
あの日から続く未来は
The future that continues from that day
みんなとつかんだ今日だよ
Is the today we grabbed together
もっと もっと もっと もっと 加速するハート
More and more and more and more, my heart accelerates
一緒に行くよ どこまでも 準備はOK?
I'll go with you anywhere. Are you ready?
ひらけ 夢の扉を
Open the door to dreams
1, 2, 3! キラメキライダー
1, 2, 3! Kirameki Rider
生まれたてのドキドキを響かせよう
Let the newborn heart-throb resound
最高の時間 最高の仲間と
The best time with the best friends
ここにいるよ 見つけてくれたから
I'm here because you found me
君に会いたくて やってきたんだ みんなで歌おう
I came here because I wanted to see you. Let's sing together
終わらないメロディー
The never-ending melody
キラメキにのって Yeah!
Ride on the sparkle, Yeah!
ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
届いてるかな？私の声
Is my voice reaching you?
届けたいのは 君へ笑顔
What I want to deliver is a smile to you
理想の遠さに悔しくて
Frustrated by how far my ideals were
みんなと泣き笑ったね
We cried and laughed together
ぎゅっと ぎゅっと ぎゅっと ぎゅっと 全て抱きしめて
Tightly, tightly, tightly, tightly, embrace everything
一緒に行こう どこまでも 準備はOK?
Let's go together anywhere. Are you ready?
進め 希望の道を
Forward on the path of hope
1, 2, 3! キラメキライダー
1, 2, 3! Kirameki Rider
好きな気持ち カラフルに奏でたいんだ
I want to play my feelings of love colorfully
最高の場所 最高の皆と
The best place with the best everyone
ここにいるよ 幻なんかじゃない
I'm here, it's not an illusion
君の心が幸せに染まるように
So that your heart may be dyed with happiness
重ねていくハーモニー
Layers of harmony
キラメキまとって
Clad in sparkle
歌い続けたいな 踊り続けたいな
I want to keep singing, I want to keep dancing
そんな願い 我がままでもいいでしょう
Even if that wish is selfish, it's okay, right?
だって楽しすぎて止まらない
Because it's so fun, I can't stop
輝くステージでもっともっと お願い ずっと！
On the shining stage, more and more, please, forever!
今日は、本当にたくさん楽しく、楽しんでいくぞー！
Today, I'm going to have so much fun, so much fun!
みんなもいっぱい楽しんでってねー！
Everyone, please enjoy yourselves a lot too!
嬉しい 楽しい 愛しい だけじゃ語れない
Happy, fun, precious... those words aren't enough
今も今も悩みはあるけれど
Even now, even now, there are worries
ここにいるよ 私ここにおるよ
I'm here, I am right here
君と同じ世界を見つめて
Gazing at the same world as you
行くよ！キラメキライダー
Here we go! Kirameki Rider
生まれたてのドキドキを響かせよう
Let the newborn heart-throb resound
最高の時間 最高の仲間と
The best time with the best friends
ここにいるよ 見つけてくれたから
I'm here because you found me
キラメキライダー☆
Kirameki Rider☆
春風が吹き抜けたんだ みんなで歌おう
The spring breeze blew through, let's all sing together
終わらないメロディ
...an endless melody.
きらめきに乗って ふらめき纏って
Riding the sparkle, wearing the flutter,
揺らめき纏って
wearing the shimmer.
Yeah!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
キラメキライダーでした！
That was Kirameki Rider!
というわけで...
And so...
...みなさーん！こんばんみぉーん！
...everyone! Good evening-mio!
大神ミオでーす！
This is Ookami Mio!
Yeah!
あ、みんなすごい。2周年お祝いしてくれて本当にどうもありがとう。
Ah, you guys are amazing. Thank you so much for celebrating my 2nd anniversary.
そ、ちょっと1曲目からね、激しめな曲だったので少し息が上がっております。
I'm a bit out of breath because the first song was so intense.
あ！あ、ちょっとおもらししちゃいましたね。
Ah! Ah, I leaked a little bit, didn't I?
すみません。ははは。
Sorry. Hahaha.
パチパチありがとうございます。
Thank you for the applause.
いや、2周年ありがとうございます。
Man, thank you for these two years.
本当に応援してくれるみなさんのおかげで、3年目をこれから歩き出そうとしております。
Thanks to all of you who support me, I'm about to start my third year.
ちょっとね、あのこれから曲続くんですけどもね、
There are more songs coming up, but
ちょいちょいMCを挟みながらみんなと今日は楽しんでいけたらいいなと思っておりますので、どうぞよろしくお願いいたします。
I'll have some MC breaks here and there. I hope we can all have fun together today!
というわけで、早速2曲目いっちゃおうかな？ちょっとおもらししちゃったけど。
So, shall we get right into the second song? Even though I leaked a bit.
じゃあ、2曲目お願いします！
Alright, here is the second song!
Don't say "lazy"
作詞：大森祥子 / 作曲：前澤寛之
Lyrics: Shoko Omori / Composition: Hiroyuki Maezawa
Please don't say you are lazy
だって本当はcrazy
Because I'm actually crazy
白鳥たちはそう 見えないところでバタ足するんです
Swans, you see, paddle hard where no one can see
本能に忠順忠実
Obedient and faithful to instinct
煩悩も重々承知
Fully aware of my own desires
前途洋々だし だからたまに休憩したいんです
The future is bright, so I want to rest sometimes
Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey!
この目でしっかり見定めて 行き先
Identify the destination clearly with these eyes,
地図上マークして
marking it on the map.
近道あれば それが王道
If there's a shortcut, that's the royal road.
端折れる翼もあれば上等
Wings that can skip the path are even better.
ヤバ 爪割れた
Oh no, I broke a nail.
グルーで補修した
Fixed it with some glue.
それだけで なんか達成感
I feel a sense of accomplishment just from that.
大事なのは自分 かわいがること
The important thing is to be kind to yourself.
自分を愛さなきゃ 他人も愛せない
If you don't love yourself, you can't love others.
Please don't say you are lazy
だって本当はcrazy
Because I'm actually crazy
能ある鷹はそう 見えないところにピック隠すんです
A skilled hawk hides its pick where no one can see
想像に一生懸命
Putting all effort into imagination
現実は絶体絶命
The reality is a desperate situation
発展途上だし だからたまにピッチ外れるんです
I'm still developing, so I get off pitch sometimes
Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey!
どんどんいくぞー！
Let's keep going!
この目に映らないだけで
Just because you can't see it,
やる気はメーター振り切って
my motivation is off the charts.
いつでも全力で夢見て
Always dreaming with all my might,
その分全力で眠って
sleeping just as hard afterwards.
やり遂げた感で
With a sense of achievement,
調子づいて食った
I got carried away and ate too much.
それだけで 何で敗北感
Why do I feel so defeated just from that?
すかさずに目標を下方修正して
Quickly lowering my goals,
柔軟に臨機応変 七変化が勝ち
flexibility and adaptation are key to winning.
Please don't say you are lazy
だって本当はcrazy
Because I'm actually crazy
孔雀たちはそう ここぞという時美を見せるんです
Peacocks, you see, show their beauty when it matters most
五臓六腑邁進
Pushing forward with my whole soul
願望は疎志ネジ
Desire is the engine
誘惑多発しだし だからやけに意志砕けちゃうんです
Temptations keep coming, so my will easily breaks
Woo!
みんな楽しんでるかー！
Is everyone having fun?!
すごいよー！
This is amazing!
ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
Don't say lazy
うちもめっちゃ楽しんでるよー！
I'm having a blast too!
やばっ　まさか　留年ぽい
Oh no, don't tell me, I might fail this grade
いや　ギリクリア
No, barely passed
それだけで　めでたし　満足感
Just with that, I'm happy and satisfied
大事なのは自分　可愛がること
What's important is taking care of yourself
自分を許さなきゃ　他人も許せない
If you don't forgive yourself, you can't forgive others
Please don't say "You are lazy"
だって本当は crazy
Because actually, I'm crazy
白鳥たちはそう　見えないとこでバタ足するんです
Like swans, we're paddling frantically beneath the surface
本能に従順　忠実
Compliant and faithful to instinct
翻弄も重々承知
Well aware of being trifled with
前途洋々だし　だからたまに休憩しちゃうんです
The future is bright, so I take a break now and then
ありがとうー！
Thank you!
わー！2周年お祝いのケーキだ！嬉しい！
Wow! It's a 2nd anniversary celebration cake! I'm so happy!
いただきまーす！
Let's eat!
んー！甘くて美味しい！
Mmm! It's sweet and delicious!
もういっちょ！
Another bite!
んー！最高だね！
Mmm! This is the best!
美味しい、美味しい！
Delicious, delicious!
いや、これは、これはこれは、もう、これクリーミーですね！
Wow, this is... this is really... man, it's so creamy!
みんなも食べたいでしょ？
You guys want some too, right?
あーん...あげないけどね！
Say 'ahhh'... but I'm not giving you any!
あ！ラスト行こうか！もう一個！
Ah! Let's go for the last one! One more!
んー！完食！
Mmm! All finished!
おかゆー！
Okayu!
深愛 / 作詞：水樹奈々 / 作曲：上松範康
Shin-ai / Lyrics: Nana Mizuki / Comp: Noriyasu Agematsu
雪が舞い散る夜空
The night sky where snow dances down
二人寄り添い見上げた
Two of us snuggled up and looked up
繋がる手と手の温もりは
The warmth of our joined hands
とても優しかった
Was very gentle
淡いオールドブルーの
In the pale old blue
雲間に消えてゆくでしょう
It will likely vanish between the clouds
永遠へと続くはずの
What should have lasted for eternity
あの約束
That promise
あなたの側にいるだけで
Just by being by your side
ただそれだけでよかった
That alone was enough
いつのまにか膨らむ
Before I knew it, it swelled
今以上の夢に気づかずに
Without realizing it had become a bigger dream than now
どんな時も　どこにいる時でも
No matter when, no matter where I am
強く　強く　抱きしめていて
Hold me tight, hold me tight
情熱が日常に染まるとしても
Even if passion becomes mundane
あなたへのこの想いすべて
All of these feelings for you
終わりなき愛信じている
I believe in this endless love
あなただけをずっと見つめているの
I will keep watching only you forever
交わす言葉と時間
The words and time we exchange
姿を変えてゆくでしょう
They will likely change their form
白い頬に乗せたそれは
The thing placed on your white cheek
月の涙
Is a tear of the moon
行かないでともう少しだけ
Saying 'Don't go,' just a little longer
何度も言いかけては
I started to say it many times
また会えるよね　きっと
We can meet again, surely
深愛
Deep Love (Shin'ai)
...んなも
...any [difficulty]
自分に問いかける
I ask myself
突然走り出したゆめ
A dream that suddenly started running
思いきり裂いて
Searing through...
すいません 放送事故が
I'm sorry, a broadcast accident...
震えた声で
With a trembling voice
許される日が来るならば
If the day I'm forgiven comes
もう一度伝えたいよ
I want to tell you once more
すいません
I'm sorry
黙っていても届かない
It won't reach even if I'm silent
声にしなきゃ動き出さなきゃ
Must put it into words, must start moving
隠したままの二人の秘密
The secret of the two of us kept hidden
このまま忘れられてしまうの
Will it be forgotten like this?
だからね早く
So, quickly
今ここに来て
Come here now
ケーキ食べすぎちまったかもしれねぇ
I might've eaten too much cake...
あなたのそばにいるだけで
Just being by your side
ただそれだけでよかった
That alone was enough
今度巡り逢えたら
If we can meet again next time
もっともっと笑い合えるかな
I wonder if we can laugh together more and more
どんな時もどこにいる時でも
No matter when, no matter where we are
強く強く抱きしめていて
Hold me tight, tight
情熱より熱い熱で溶かして
Melt it with heat hotter than passion
一つだけこの想いは全て
This feeling is everything
終わりなどないと信じている
I believe there is no end
あなただけずっと見つめているの
I'm only looking at you forever
なま、なまだから、なまだから
It's raw, because it's raw, because it's raw
生ケーキもなまだったけど
The fresh cake was raw too, but
なまだから
Because it's raw...
えっと、あ、ここであの
Um, ah, at this point...
すいませんあの
I'm sorry, um...
ちょっとこんな、こんなこと
After this kind of, this kind of...
こんなことになったあとなんですけどあの
...thing happening, but um...
あの、ゲストがいます
Um, there's a guest.
えー、おーい！おーい！
Eh, hey! Hey!
キツネやーい！キツネやーい！
Fox! Hey! Fox! Hey!
白上フブキ
Shirakami Fubuki
あ、いた。こんなとこにいた。
Ah, there she is. She was in a place like this.
キツネ！どうにかしてくれこの空気
Fox! Do something about this atmosphere!
もうどうしよううち
What should I do?
おめえ歌舞いの転換の時にケーキなんか食ってるからだろ
That's because you were eating cake during the scene change!
やっちまった！やっちまった！
I messed up! I messed up!
食べたいとか言いながら、あげるもしなかったからだろ
It's 'cause you said you wanted it but didn't even share, right?
ごめん、ごめん、うちが全部一人で食べちゃったから
Sorry, sorry, it's because I ate it all by myself.
大丈夫だよミアン、あ、ミオ、だって足元雪だからさ
It's okay Mian—ah, Mio. I mean, there's snow at your feet.
ケーキ白いからわかんない
The cake is white, so you can't tell.
余計わかるだろうが！
That makes it even more obvious!
それはわかるよ
I can tell that much.
大丈夫、見えない見えない
It's fine, you can't see it, you can't see it.
わかんないかな
Can't you tell?
見えない、見えない大丈夫大丈夫。うん。
Can't see it, can't see it, it's fine, it's fine. Yeah.
あの、吐いてはないんですよ
Um, I didn't throw up.
吐いてないね
You didn't.
ちょっと込み上げちゃった
It just almost came up.
そう、ごめん。後ろから見守るミオが咳き込んで「ミオ！」っつって
Right, sorry. Watching Mio from behind, she coughed, and I went 'Mio!'
「大丈夫か」って小声で声が出ちゃったもん
I even whispered 'Are you okay?' out loud.
そうなんだよ。そう。リハーサル上手くいってたんだ
That's right. Yeah. The rehearsal went so well.
そう、リハーサルは、リハーサルはね、すごくね、よかったんだけどね
Yeah, the rehearsal... the rehearsal was really great, but...
ケーキ食うから。リハ食ってなかったやん、ケーキ
It's because you ate cake. You didn't eat it during rehearsal!
そうだね。あそこで食うからだよ
True. It's 'cause you ate it then.
まあまあ、これもね、ならではならでは
Well, well, this is also unique to a live show.
そうだね、ミオママ、面白かったよ
Right, Mio-mama. It was funny.
ちょっとあれはね、ちょっとえぐいやつやっちゃったね
That was a bit of a nasty one I did there.
カットされるかもしれない。普通にね放送してるときだったら
It might get cut. If it were a normal broadcast...
ボリューム絞って、レベルの咳だった
...that cough would be at a 'mute volume' level.
そうだね。超豪華
Right. It was super extravagant.
そうですね。はい。
Indeed. Yes.
というわけで、本日、え、毎年ね、うちがね周年になると現れてくれる
So, today... every year, on my anniversary, she appears...
白上フブキさんにお越しいただきましたー
Please welcome Shirakami Fubuki-san!
はーい、白上フブキです。ありがとう。
Hi, I'm Shirakami Fubuki. Thank you!
「い」っていう文字が、シャープの半分みたいに
The character 'i' looks like half of a sharp symbol.
シャープ。本当だ。なかなかにね、あの見ないフォントだよね
A sharp. You're right. It's quite a unique font, isn't it?
そうだね。髪のところもなんか、短いし。まあでも可愛い。可愛いフォントの
Yeah. The hair parts are short too. Well, it's a cute font.
はい。というわけでね。まあ、ちょっとね、2周年記念ということでライブ
Yes. So, anyway. This is my 2nd anniversary live concert.
ミオーん！
Mio-n!
早くない？
Isn't it fast?
早いね2周年。あっという間だったね。
The 2nd anniversary came so fast. It was over in a flash.
そうなんだよ。
Yeah, it really was.
ねえねえ、ここでね、ミオへのお手紙みたいな感じで泣かそうかと思ったんだけど、
You know, I thought about making you cry with a letter or something...
今回お祭りだからね。
but since this is a festival...
そうだね。
Right.
ちょっとそういうわけにはいかないと思って。
I didn't think that would be appropriate.
そうだね。この後ズビズビになっちゃうから。
Yeah. I'd be all sniffly after that.
そうそう、この後ズビズビになりながらね。
Right, all sniffly.
まだまだ曲控えてるのにってなっちゃうんだけどもう。
Even though there are more songs coming up.
いやもう本当に改めて、ミオ2周年おめでとう！
Anyway, once again, Mio, happy 2nd anniversary!
わー！ありがとう！嬉しい！
Yay! Thank you! I'm so happy.
ありがとうございます！おめでとう！
Thank you very much! Congratulations!
ねえ、1曲目から『煌めきライダー☆』ぶち込んできたね！
You threw in "Kirameki Rider" right from the first song!
いやなんか最初ぶち上げたくて！
I wanted to start with a real blast!
もう後ろで白上もずっとあの「はい！はい！」ってしてたんだけどね。
Shirakami was also doing this "Ai! Ai!" in the back the whole time.
声が入らないように頑張ってました。
I tried hard not to let my voice get picked up.
いや、そうやね。もうなんか最初から参加してもらおうかとも思ったんだけど。
Yeah, I thought about having you join from the start.
あかん！2周年記念で現れる厄介オタクみたいになっちゃうから。合いの手厄介オタクね。
No way! I'd look like a troublesome otaku showing up at your 2nd anniversary. A troublesome otaku with call and response.
「イエーイ！煌めきライダー！」つって。
"YEAH! KIRAMEKI RIDER!"
「厄介オタク、おい、やめろ、ミオのライブだぞ」って怒られちゃうんでミオファに。
The fans would get mad, "Hey, stop it, troublesome otaku, this is Mio's live!"
いや、でもさ、フブキングと一緒にカラオケやったことあるよね？
But Fubuki-ko and I have gone to karaoke together, right?
あるあるあるある。
We have, we have.
なんかその時はさ、割とあの合いの手マスターだったよね。
At that time, you were quite the call-and-response master.
やばかったね。ちょっとね、反省をした。反省をしました白上は。はい。
That was bad. I reflected on it a bit. Shirakami has reflected.
で、2曲目がORANGE RANGE。何でこれ選んだの？ミオ。
And the second song was Orange Range... why did you choose this, Mio?
あ、なんか歌いたいなって思って。
Oh, I just really felt like singing it.
そういうことか！
Is that so!
カラオケかよ！
It was like a karaoke session!
ガチカラオケだよね。
It really was!
いやでもやっぱ、カッコいいの似合うね、ミオ。
But you really suit cool songs, Mio.
ありがとう！
Thank you!
『Daidai』めっちゃ良かったもん。
"Daidai" was really great.
『Daidai』と、あと『深愛』に関してはですね、カラオケの音源を作ってもらいまして。
About "Daidai" and "Shin'ai"... I had the karaoke tracks specially made.
あ、作ってもらったんだ！
Oh, you had them made!
そうなんですよ。ありがとうございます！
Yes. Thank you very much!
一応ね、概要欄のね、スペシャルサンクスのところにもね、書いてあるんですけど、
They are listed in the Special Thanks section of the description...
え、作っていただいた方のURL載ってますので。
The URLs for the creators are linked there.
はい。ありがとうございます！
Okay. Thank you very much!
そしてね、ちょっとね、事故った『深愛』だけど。
And then "Shin'ai", though I messed up a bit...
事故った『深愛』。やめろ！事故った『深愛』って言うな！
"Mistake Shin'ai"? Stop it! Don't call it "Mistake Shin'ai"!
事故った『深愛』はちょっと聞こえが悪いぞ。
"Mistake Shin'ai" sounds a bit bad.
確かに。ま、『深愛』だけどさ。
True. It was "Shin'ai" though.
ねえ、まさかこの曲持ってくるとは思わなかった。びっくりした。
I didn't expect you to bring out this song. I was surprised.
あー、なんか水樹奈々さんの曲すごい良いなーって。
I just really love Mizuki Nana-san's songs.
良いよね、カッコいいよね。
They're great, right? So cool.
そう、だったんだけど、なかなか、こうカラオケの音源がなかったりするから、
But it's hard to find karaoke tracks for them...
なんか今回こういう機会で作っちゃおうかなって思って。
So I thought I'd take this opportunity to have one made.
おお、なるほど！
Oh, I see!
そう。好きな曲だから作ってもらったんだよね。
Yeah. I had it made because it's a song I love.
いや、良いね、『深愛』。めっちゃ良かった。
That's nice. "Shin'ai" was really good.
はい。まあ、ちょっと事故っちゃったけど。
Well, I did mess up a bit though.
事故ってなんぼのライブだと思ってるんで全然気にしないよ。
A live isn't a live without some mistakes! Don't worry about it.
なんか、じゃあこの後も事故り続けて、むしろね、もうどんどん咳き込んでコンコンしてもろて。
In fact, keep coughing and clearing your throat as you go.
あ、オッケー！
Oh, okay!
何なんだろうね。なんかね、突然出てきちゃったんだよね、なんか。
What was that, I wonder? It just came out suddenly.
もう耐えられない...いや、
I couldn't help it... no,
多分ね緊張とともにさ、ちょっと声もね、詰まっちゃうんだよね。
I think the nervousness made my voice tighten up.
そうなんだよなー。
Yeah, that's it.
みんな、いっぱい見てるからね。ほら、だって。
Look, there are so many people watching.
そう、そうなんだよ。そう思うと緊張するからね、やっぱり。
Yeah, thinking about that makes me nervous.
もうなんかさ、ステージでさ、こうやってさ、ソロでって言うのが初めてでさ。
Standing on stage alone for a solo like this for the first time...
そうだよね。
That's true.
おお。
Oh.
いや、良いね、すごいよね！
It's amazing!
じゃあミオにね、そんなミオに、ちょっとリラックス体操をね、教えようかなーって。
Well then, for Mio... I'll teach you a relaxation exercise.
え、何リラックス体操？
A relaxation exercise?
白上式リラックス体操教えようかなーって思いますので。
I'll teach you the Shirakami-style relaxation exercise.
じゃあ白上に合わせちょっと体動かしてもらっていいですか？
So, please move your body along with Shirakami.
あ、はい。
Okay.
はい、いきます。じゃあ、両手を上げて、
Here we go. Raise both hands...
両手を上げて、
Raise both hands...
ゆら〜ゆら〜揺れる〜♪
Swa-a-ay, swaying...♪
ミオ〜ン、ミオ〜ン、ミオ〜ン、ミオ〜ン、
Mio-n, mio-n, mio-n, mio-n,
ゆら〜ゆら〜ゆら〜ゆら〜、ミオ〜ン、ミオ〜ン、ミオ〜ン。
Swa-a-ay, swaying... mio-n, mio-n, mio-n.
オッケー、リラックス！
Okay, relax!
絶対即席で作っただろこれ！
You definitely made that up on the spot, didn't you?
即席で。
On the spot.
いや、でもね、これで体の力抜いて。
But this loosens up your body.
ゆら〜ゆら〜ゆら〜ゆら〜、ミオ〜ン、ミオ〜ン、ミオ〜ン。
Swa-a-ay, swaying... mio-n, mio-n, mio-n.
天才か？
Are you a genius?
いや、天才だよ白上は。ホロライブの天才って言われてるらしいからね。
Shirakami is a genius. I'm told I'm the genius of Hololive.
天才狐。自称天才狐。
The "Genius Fox". Self-proclaimed Genius Fox.
自称だった。
Self-proclaimed!
自称天才狐。
Self-proclaimed Genius Fox.
やべ、なんかフブキとこのまま喋ってるとこのまま1時間過ぎちゃいそう。
Man, if I keep talking with Fubuki, an hour will pass just like that.
それ！
Exactly!
まずいまずいまずい。
That's bad.
はい。じゃあね、お祝いということで、改めてミオ、本当におめでとう！
So, once again, Mio, congratulations!
ありがとう！わー、ありがた、ありがた。
Yay! Thank you! Thank you so much!
ね、3年目のミオを、
And for Mio's 3rd year...
3年目のミオを...
Mio's 3rd year...
ね。はい。よろしくお願いします！
Yes, please take care of her.
皆さんよろしくお願いします！
Everyone, please take care of me!
ということでね、これからもまだまだね、曲が残ってますので。
We still have more songs to go.
ミオファの皆さんは全力で色々振ってもらってね。ペンライト、バカ振ってもらって。
So, Mio-fa, please wave your lightsticks with all your might.
はい。そしてそしてね、ミオのスクショでいっぱいっぱい撮ってください。
And take lots of screenshots of Mio!
はい。撮ってください。よろしくお願いします。
Please do! We count on you.
そしてね、右上にありますハッシュタグ #大神ミオ2周年 で、ぜひともツイッター、
And please tweet with the hashtag #大神ミオ2周年 in the upper right.
それそれそれ、ミオ届く？手、届く？
That one, that one. Can you reach it, Mio?
おりゃー！
Hup!
届いたー！普通に届いた！ね、たくさん呟いてください。はい、お願いします。
She reached it! Please tweet a lot.
よろしくお願いします。
Please do.
というわけでね、フブキにはね、またちょっと、お、手ほど、ちょっとだけ登場してもらおうかなーと思ってるんだけど。
Fubuki will be appearing again in a little bit.
はい！
Yes!
はい。この後また見守り係に入っていただ、いただこうと思います。
I'll have her come back as a watcher later.
見守り係でーす！
I'm the watcher!
はーい！
See you!
本当にいつもありがとうね。
Thank you truly, as always.
いやいや、ありがとうミオみーん。
No no, thank you, Mio-mion.
昨日のポップコーンも良かったよ。
Yesterday's popcorn was great too.
あれは黒歴史だよ。
That's a part of my "black history" (embarrassing past).
やめてくれ！
Stop it!
あの企画が黒歴史みたいに…
That project is like a dark past...
やめてくれ！そんなことない。
Stop it! That's not true.
第二回もやります。
We're doing a second round of it too.
あー、頑張ってね。
Ah, good luck with that.
はい、ありがとうございました。
Okay, thank you very much.
さらだばー！
Farewell!
さらだばー！さらだばー！
Farewell! Farewell!
はい、というわけで白上フブキはこのまま見守り体制に入っていただきますが…
Well then, Shirakami Fubuki will stay on in "monitoring mode" for now...
このあと、えと、うちは、ええ、別の曲が始まりますので…
...but after this, I'll be starting the next song.
みんなも本当にどうもありがとう。
Everyone, really, thank you so much.
今日さ、すごいっぱいさ、メンバー入ってくれてる人いてさ、すごいびっくりした。
I was really surprised to see so many people joining as members today.
ありがとうね。あすぱちゃもありがとうございます、本当に。
Thank you. And thank you truly for the superchats as well.
あの、後ほどね、あすぱ見ながら雑談とかもしようかと思っておりますので…
I'm thinking of doing a chat stream while going through them later...
本当にありがとうございました。
So, thank you very much.
あー、調整中、調整中、あー、あー。はいというわけで…
Ah, testing, testing, ah, ah. All right then...
えー、ではこれからミオのライブもうちょっとだけ続くんじゃよ。
Well, Mio's live will continue for just a bit longer.
では次の曲よろしくお願いします。
Now, please enjoy the next song.
粉雪
作詞・作曲：藤巻亮太
Powder Snow
Lyrics & Composition: Ryota Fujimaki
みんなコメントで盛り上げて！
Everyone, liven things up in the comments!
例のサビのところで盛り上げてくださいね！
Please liven it up at that chorus part!
粉雪舞う季節は
In the season when powder snow dances
いつもすれ違い
We always pass each other by
人混みに紛れても
Even when lost in the crowd
同じ空見てるのに
Even though we're looking at the same sky
風に吹かれて
Blown by the wind
似たように凍えるのに
Even though we're freezing in the same way
僕は君のすべてなど
I'm sure I don't know...
知ってはいないだろう
...everything about you
それでも一億人から
Even so, from among a hundred million people
君を見つけたよ
I found you
根拠はないけど
There's no basis for it, but...
本気で思ってるんだ
...I truly believe it
同じ時間を生きてなどいけない
We can't live through the same time
素直になれないなら
If we can't be honest...
喜びも悲しみも
...then both joy and sadness...
虚しいだけ
...are just empty
粉雪ね
Powder snow, huh...
心まで白く染められたなら
If even my heart could be dyed white...
二人の孤独を分け合うことができたのかい
...would we have been able to share our loneliness?
僕は君の心に
I'll put my ear...
耳を押しあてて
...to your heart
その声のするほうへ
Towards where that voice comes from...
スッと深くまで
...and straight down to the depths...
下りてゆきたい
...I want to descend
ここでもう一度会おう
Let's meet here once more
分かり合いたいなんて
To say I want to understand each other...
上辺を撫でていたのは僕のほう
...it was me who was just scratching the surface
君のかじかんだ手を
Your frozen hands...
握りしめることだけで
...just by squeezing them tightly...
繋がってたのに
...we were connected, and yet...
粉雪ね
Powder snow, huh...
時に頼りなく
Sometimes unreliable...
...ああまりにもろく... あはは...
...it's just so fragile... Ah-ha-ha...
ザラつくアスファルトの上 シミになってゆくよ
On the rough asphalt, it turns into a stain
粉雪ねえ 時に頼りなく
Powdered snow, hey, sometimes helplessly
心は揺れる あはは...
My heart wavers, Ah-ha-ha...
それでも僕は君のこと
Even so, for you
守り続けたい
I want to keep protecting you
粉雪ねえ 心まで白く
Powdered snow, hey, if even my heart
染められたなら あはは...
Could be dyed white, Ah-ha-ha...
二人の孤独を包んで
Wrapping up our loneliness
空に返すから
And returning it to the sky
お疲れ様でした。
Good work everyone.
頑張りました。
I did my best.
ちょっと一回、ちょっぴり休憩を挟ませてもらおうかな。
I think I'll take a little bit of a break.
ミオーン！
Mio-n!
すみませんでした。本当にすみませんでした。
I'm sorry. I'm really sorry.
何かこう、始まってしまいましたね。咳から。
Something has, like, started. From a cough.
ちょっとじゃあ、ちょっぴり休憩をさせていただいて、
So, I'll take a little break,
その間にちょっと、何かこう、きっと何かが変わると思うので。
and in the meantime, I think something will surely change.
何かが変わって... あ、あの、えっと、あの...
Something will change... ah, um, er, that...
ステージが変わって、ステージも変わって、うちも変わると思います。
The stage will change, the stage will also change, and I think I'll change too.
お！なのでちょっと皆さんね、ちょっとだけ休憩もらってもいいですか？
Oh! So everyone, can I have just a little break?
ミオーン！ありがとうございます。
Mio-n! Thank you.
運営さん、そうですね。ちょっとあの動画を流してくれるそうなので、
Staff-san, yes. It seems they'll play a video for us,
皆さんそちらを、どうぞ！
so everyone, please watch that!
どこに？
To where?
わあ！2周年お祝いのケーキだ！嬉しい！
Wow! A 2nd anniversary celebration cake! I'm so happy!
いただきまーす。
Let's eat.
はむ、はむ、はむ。
Munch, munch, munch.
うーん、甘くて美味しい！
Mmm, sweet and delicious!
もう一口、はむはむはむ。
Another bite, munch munch munch.
うーん、最高だね。はむはむはむはむ。
Mmm, this is the best. Munch munch munch munch.
美味しい、美味しい。はむ、はむはむはむ。
Tasty, tasty. Munch, munch munch munch.
あ、いやこれは、これはこれは、もうこれクリーミーですね。
Ah, no, this is, this is... it's just so creamy.
はむはむはむ、うーん、美味しい！
Munch munch munch, mmm, delicious!
みんなも食べたいでしょう、あー。
You all want to eat some too, right? Ahh—
あげないけどねー。はむはむはむはむ。
But I'm not giving you any. Munch munch munch munch.
もう一口、あー、はむはむはむはむ。
One more bite, ahh— munch munch munch munch.
あ！もうラスト一個か。もう一個、はむはむはむ。
Ah! Just one last piece? One more, munch munch munch.
うーん！完食！お粥！
Mmm! Finished it! Okayu!
わあ！2周年お祝いのケーキだ！嬉しい！
Wow! A 2nd anniversary celebration cake! I'm so happy!
いただきまーす。
Let's eat.
はむ、はむ、はむ。
Munch, munch, munch.
うーん、甘くて美味しい！
Mmm, sweet and delicious!
もう一口、はむはむはむ。
Another bite, munch munch munch.
うーん、最高だね。はむはむはむはむ。
Mmm, this is the best. Munch munch munch munch.
美味しい、美味しい。はむ、はむはむはむ。
Tasty, tasty. Munch, munch munch munch.
あ、いやこれは、これはこれは、もうこれクリーミーですね。
Ah, no, this is, this is... it's just so creamy.
はむはむはむ、うーん、美味しい！
Munch munch munch, mmm, delicious!
みんなも食べたいでしょう、あー。
You all want to eat some too, right? Ahh—
あげないけどねー。はむはむはむはむ。
But I'm not giving you any. Munch munch munch munch.
もう一口、あー、はむはむはむはむ。
One more bite, ahh— munch munch munch munch.
あ！もうラスト一個か。もう一個、はむはむはむ。
Ah! Just one last piece? One more, munch munch munch.
うーん！完食！お粥！
Mmm! Finished it! Okayu!
あれから僕たちは 何かを信じてこれたかな
Since then, I wonder if we've been able to believe in something.
夜空のむこうには 明日がもう待っている
Beyond the night sky, tomorrow is already waiting.
Wooah...
誰かの声に気づき 僕らは身をひそめた
Noticing someone's voice, we hid ourselves away.
公園のフェンス越しに 夜の風が吹いた
Across the park fence, the night wind blew.
君が何か伝えようと 握り返したその手は
That hand you squeezed back, as if to tell me something...
僕の心のやわらかい場所を
Even now, it still tightens up
今でもまだ締めつける
the softest part of my heart.
あれから僕たちは 何かを信じてこれたかな
Since then, I wonder if we've been able to believe in something.
窓をそっと開けてみる 冬の風の匂いがした
I gently open the window; it smelled like the winter wind.
悲しみっていつかは
I wonder if sadness
消えてしまうものなのかな
is something that eventually disappears.
ため息は少しだけ 白く残ってすぐ消えた
My sigh lingered white for a moment, then vanished.
歩き出すことさえも いちいちためらうくせに
Even though I hesitate at every single step...
つまらない常識など 潰せると思ってた
I thought I could crush such boring common sense.
君に話した言葉は どれだけ残っているの
How many of the words I said to you still remain?
僕の心のいちばん奥で
In the deepest part of my heart,
空回りしつづける
they continue to spin in vain.
あの頃の未来に 僕らは立っているのかな
I wonder if we're standing in the future we imagined back then.
全てが思うほど うまくは行かないみたいだ
It seems like not everything goes as well as one hopes.
このままどこまでも 日々は続いていくのかな
I wonder if these days will continue on like this forever.
雲のない星空が 窓の向こうに続いてる
A cloudless starry sky continues beyond the window.
あれから僕たちは 何かを信じてこれたかな
Since then, I wonder if we've been able to believe in something.
夜空のむこうには もう明日が待っている
Beyond the night sky, tomorrow is already waiting.
Wooah...
えっと、ところ変わって、こちらはビルの屋上となっております。
Um, the location has changed, and we are now on a building's rooftop.
えー、まぁちょっとですね、
Uh, well, you see,
あのー夜景で大人っぽく、「夜空のむこう」でいこうかなと。
I thought I'd go with 'Yozora no Mukou' for a mature vibe with the night view.
お水ありがとうございます、フクシマミカさん、えー。
Thank you for the water, Fukushima Mika-san. Uh...
へへ、そういう感じで、
Hehe, so like...
えー、歌わせていただきました。
...that's how I sang it.
「夜空の向こう」ありがとうございましたー！
Thank you for "Yozora no Mukou"!
ありがとーー！
Thank you!
というわけで、えー、
So, well...
そうですね。
Yeah...
まあ、ちょっと、もうちょっとかっこいい曲歌ってもいいんじゃないかなと思って
I thought it would be good to sing
a slightly cooler song...
もう一曲選曲してみたんですけれども。
...so I chose another song.
この夜景のバックで
With this night view in the background...
もう一曲、皆さんに、
...I'd like to show you all another...
かっこいい大神ミオを
...cool Ookami Mio.
見せたいと思います！
I want to show you!
へへ。ちょっとつまづいちゃったりもしたけど、
Hehe. I tripped a little bit...
今回は、ちゃんとビシッと決めたいなーって、
But this time, I want to nail it perfectly.
頑張りたいなーと思ってますので、
I want to do my best...
見守りよろしくお願いします！
...so please keep an eye on me.
はい。
Yes.
あ、すごい！今、
Oh, wow! Just now...
白上フブキお水係に
...Shirakami Fubuki, the "water-pourer"...
Twitterのトレンド1位になってるよって教えてもらった！
...told me that "Mio Mizukakari" is
trending #1 on Twitter!
ありがとうみんなーー！
Thank you everyone!
つぶやきありがとうー！
Thank you for the tweets!
皆さんのつぶやき後で巡回しようと思ってますので、
I'll take a look at everyone's
tweets later.
少し、スクショなども、ぜひぜひよろしくお願いします。パチパチ。
So please keep posting screenshots
and stuff. *snap snap*
というわけで、えー、
Anyway, well...
ちょっとかっこいい大神ミオを見せれたらいいなと思っておりますので、
I hope I can show you a cool Ookami Mio.
皆さん、ぜひ、次の曲も楽しみにしてて下さいね！
Everyone, please look forward to
the next song too!
盛り上がっていくぞーー！
Let's get hyped up!
というわけで、運営さん、
So, staff-san...
よろしくお願いします！
...please take it away!
ノーザンクロス
作詞：岩里祐穂・Gabriela Robin／作曲：菅野よう子
Northern Cross
Lyrics: Yuho Iwasato, Gabriela Robin / Music: Yoko Kanno
旅の始まりは もう思い出せない
I can no longer remember the beginning of the journey
気づいたら ここにいた
By the time I noticed, I was already here
季節が破けて 見入る赤外線 感じる眼が
Seasons are torn, looking into the infrared,
the feeling eyes...
迷子になる 多分知るのだ 命がけの想い
...get lost. Perhaps they know of this
life-risking feeling.
戦うように恋した
I fell in love as if fighting
ひたすらに夢を掘った
I dug for my dreams single-mindedly
その星に降り立たった
I landed on that star
君の空 飛びたかった
I wanted to fly in your sky
誰か 僕の輪郭を そっと撫でてくれないか
Won't someone gently stroke my silhouette?
胸の鼓動に蹴飛ばされて 転がり出た愛の言葉
Kicked by the beating of my heart,
words of love came rolling out
だけど 困ったな 答えがない
But I'm in trouble, there is no answer
宿命に貼り付けられた 北極星が燃えてる
Nailed to fate, the North Star is burning
君をかきむしって濁らせた なのに可憐に笑うとこ
I clawed at you and made you cloudy,
yet you smile so prettily...
好き勝手
...as you please.
君がいないなら
If you aren't here
意味なんて なくなるから
Because meaning will disappear
一は全部 消えればいい
It'd be better if everyone disappeared
愛がなくなれば
If love disappears
心だって いらないから
Because I won't even need a heart
この世界も 消えてしまえ
May this world also vanish
ずっと苦しかった 命がけの出会い
It's always been painful,
this life-risking encounter
もがくように夢見た
I dreamed as if struggling
闇雲に手を伸ばした
I reached out blindly
その胸に聞きかった
I wanted to ask that heart
君と虹 かけたかった
I wanted to build a rainbow with you
誰か 夜明けの感傷で ギュッと抱いてくれないか
Won't someone hold me tight with
the sentimentality of dawn?
夢の軌道に弾かれて 飛び散るだけの愛の涙
Repelled by the orbit of dreams,
tears of love only scatter
それが剥き出しの痛みでもいい
Even if it's a bare pain, it's fine
宿命に呼び戻された 北極星が泣いてる
Summoned back by fate, the North Star is crying
どうせ目いっぱい生き抜くなら 君を尽きるまで愛して
Since I'm going to live life to the fullest anyway,
I'll love you until you're gone...
死にたいよ
...and then I want to die.
そして始まるのだ 命がけの終わり
And so it begins, the life-risking end
戦うように愛して
Loving as if fighting
グシャグシャに夢を蹴った
I kicked my dreams into a mess
その星に果てたかった
I wanted to perish on that star
君と空
You and the sky...
ああー おおー
Aaaah... oh...
誰か 今日の輪郭を
Someone, today's silhouette...
そっとなでてくれないか
...won't you gently stroke it?
時の波動にかき消されて救えなかった愛の言葉
Words of love drowned out by the waves of time, unable to be saved
だからもう一度 答えが欲しい
So, once more, I want an answer
宿命に張り付けられた
Pinned down by destiny,
北極星が燃えている
the North Star is burning.
君をかきむしって焦がせた
I clawed at you and made you burn,
なのに可憐に笑うとこ
yet, the way you smile so prettily...
君をかきむしって焦がせた
I clawed at you and made you burn,
なのに可憐に笑うとこ
yet, the way you smile so prettily...
好きだよ おおー
I love you. Oh...
あー 久しぶりの3D我が家だー
Ah, it's been a while since I was in my 3D home.
ああー
Aaaah...
せっかくの3Dなので渾身の1発ギャグをお願いします！
Since it's a rare 3D occasion, please do your best one-shot gag!
え？ 1発ギャグですか？
Eh? A one-shot gag?
せっかくくつろいでたのになあ。
And I was just starting to relax.
まあでもね、みんなも遠路はるばるうちの3D我が家まで
Well, but you know, everyone has come all this way
遊びに来てくれたわけですから
to visit my 3D home.
まあ、みんなが喜んでくれるような...
Well, something that'll make everyone happy...
じゃあ、せっかくなんで1発ギャグやらせていただきますか！
Then, since we're here, let's do a one-shot gag!
それでは参ります。
Here we go.
大神ミオの1発ギャグシリーズ！
Ookami Mio's one-shot gag series!
まぐろ！
Tuna!
ピチピチピチピチピチ！
Flop flop flop flop flop!
わあー！
Waaaah!
あ...
Ah...
なんだ？ 今のは一体。
What was that just now?
落ちた？ 落ちたのか？
I fell? Did I fall?
まぐろは前に見たので別の1発ギャグをお願いします！
I've seen the tuna one before, so please do a different one-shot gag!
えー！ なんだよ。
Eh?! What?!
なんか分かんないけど...
I don't really get it, but...
まぐろじゃダメなのかよー！
The tuna one is no good?!
仕方ないなあ。じゃあちょっと
Can't be helped then. Well then...
考えさせていただきますが、そうですね。
...let me think. Let's see.
やっぱり動物シリーズがいいかなと思うので。
I think the animal series would be good after all.
では、大神ミオの1発ギャグシリーズ！ えっと...
Then, Ookami Mio's one-shot gag series! Let's see...
じゃ、やらせていただきます。いきます。
Okay, here I go.
よ！
Hup!
また落とすんじゃないだろうなあ。
They're not gonna drop me again, are they?
いきます。
Here I go.
とう！
Tou!
おおーおおーおおーおおー！
Ooo-ooo-ooo-ooo!
わあー！
Waaaah!
あー 久しぶりの3D我が家だー
Ah, it's been a while since I was in my 3D home.
ああー
Aaaah...
せっかくの3Dなので渾身の1発ギャグをお願いします！
Since it's a rare 3D occasion, please do your best one-shot gag!
え？ 1発ギャグですか？
Eh? A one-shot gag?
せっかくくつろいでたのになあ。
And I was just starting to relax.
まあでもね、みんなも遠路はるばるうち의 3D我が家まで
Well, but you know, everyone has come all this way
遊びに来てくれたわけですから
to visit my 3D home.
まあ、みんなが喜んでくれるような...
Well, something that'll make everyone happy...
じゃあ、せっかくなんで1発ギャグやらせていただきますか！
Then, since we're here, let's do a one-shot gag!
それでは参ります。
Here we go.
大神ミオの1発ギャグシリーズ！
Ookami Mio's one-shot gag series!
まぐろ！
Tuna!
ピチピチピチピチピチ！
Flop flop flop flop flop!
わあー！
Waaaah!
あ...
Ah...
なんだ？ 今のは一体。
What was that just now?
落ちた？ 落ちたのか？
I fell? Did I fall?
まぐろは前に見たので別の1発ギャグをお願いします！
I've seen the tuna one before, so please do a different one-shot gag!
えー！ なんだよ。
Eh?! What?!
なんか分かんないけど...
I don't really get it, but...
まぐろじゃダメなのかよー！
The tuna one is no good?!
仕方ないなあ。じゃあちょっと
Can't be helped then. Well then...
考えさせていただきますが、そうですね。
...let me think. Let's see.
やっぱり動物シリーズがいいかなと思うので。
I think the animal series would be good after all.
では、大神ミオの1発ギャグシリーズ！ えっと...
Then, Ookami Mio's one-shot gag series! Let's see...
行きます。
I'm going.
よっ。
Heave-ho.
また落とすんじゃねーだろうな？
You're not going to drop me again, are you?
えー、行きます。
Uh, here I go.
とうっ！
Hah!
お、お、お、お、お、お、お、お...
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa...
うわああああ！
Waaaaah!
あれ？
Huh?
無限ループって怖いね。
Infinite loops are scary, aren't they?
え？怖くないの？何で2回流れた？今。
Eh? Isn't it scary? Why did it play twice just now?
おつみお。さっき画面がまた自宅だったね。
Otsu-Mio. The screen was back at your house just now, wasn't it?
あ、でもよかったね！今度2周目の世界線ではステージにたどり着けたよ、ミオ。
Ah, but thank goodness! On this second world-line loop, you managed to reach the stage, Mio.
なるほど！
I see!
はい。ここにたどり着くまでに、あのループで何回も落ちてたってこと？
Yes. So you're saying I fell many times in that loop before reaching here?
そうそうそうそう。
Exactly, exactly.
えぇー。じゃあ、あそこのループに閉じ込められたうちもいるってこと？
Ehh. So there's another "me" trapped in that loop?
そうだね。
That's right.
怖すぎだろ！
That's way too scary!
大丈夫、大丈夫。閉じ込められたミオが頑張って出てこようとしてるかもしれないけど、
It's okay, it's okay. The trapped Mio might be trying hard to get out, but...
このミオはステージに来れました。
...this Mio made it to the stage.
なるほど。
I see.
そう。というわけで皆さん、アイドルステージに帰ってきましたよ！
Right. And so, everyone, I've returned to the idol stage!
おかえり！
Welcome back!
ただいま！
I'm home!
ミオ、一周してクルクルクルってやって。
Mio, do a 360 turn, spin around!
アイドル衣装、見せろ見せろ、もっと。
Show off your idol outfit, show us more.
はい。クルクルクルクルクル。
Okay. Spin, spin, spin, spin.
かわいい！
Cute!
はは。
Haha.
かわいいかよ、もう。
So cute, honestly.
いや、なかなかね、アイドル衣装を着る機会ないからね。
Well, there aren't many opportunities to wear the idol outfit, you know.
本当だよ。
That's true.
あ、今日接近カメラないの？辛いなー。
Oh, no close-up camera today? That's rough.
そんなのもありましたね。
That was a thing too, wasn't it?
そうだ、接近カメラね、欲しかったね。
Right, I wanted a close-up camera.
ガチ恋距離ないんですか、カメラさん？
Is there no "Gachikoi" distance, Mr. Camera Man?
ミオのガチ恋距離ないんですか？
No Gachikoi distance for Mio?
うちが近づいたほうがいいのかな？
Should I move closer?
よ、どうなんだ、カメラさん？顔アップ...
Yo, what's the deal, camera man? Close-up face...
え、それやば！え、それやば、ミオ！
Whoa, that's crazy! Whoa, that's crazy, Mio!
みんな、見てる？
Everyone, are you watching?
それは可愛い、ミオ。
That's so cute, Mio.
お、近い！来た来た来た！すごい！
Oh, so close! Here it comes! Amazing!
カメラさん。ちょ、待って、恥ずかしいので、ちょっとそんな近くに...
Mr. Camera Man. W-wait, I'm getting embarrassed, so don't get *that* close...
そんなことない、そんなことない。待って待って、クリーム付いてた？
Not at all, not at all. Wait, wait, was there cream on you?
見せろ見せろ、やめてやめて。サンホールも食ったろ。
Show us, show us! Stop, stop! You ate the Sunhole too, right?
付いてない、付いてないもう。
There's nothing on me, nothing anymore.
うふふ。
Hehe.
サンホールも食べたミオ。
Mio, who ate the Sunhole.
確かにサンホール食べた。結構重いね、やっぱりね。
I did indeed eat the Sunhole. It's pretty heavy, after all.
本当だよ。みんな今のスクショしたか？ちゃんと。
True that. Did everyone get a screenshot of that? Make sure you did.
今のはちょっとガチ恋距離っていうか、もう接触距離だよ。
That wasn't just Gachikoi distance, it was practically contact distance.
いいじゃん、もう接触。
It's fine, contact is good.
接触距離助かる。
Contact distance is a lifesaver.
助からない助からない。ミオミオ！
Not really, not really. Mio-Mio!
なんと！次で最後の曲。
And now! The next one is the last song.
そうなんだよ。
That's right.
やだー！
Nooo!
延長しろ！延長しろ！わーわー！
Encore! Encore! Waa waa!
捏ねるんじゃねー。
Don't start complaining.
というわけでですね、えーと、ま、最後の曲なんですけれども。
And so, well, it's the last song.
最後はね、ちょっとフブキにも一緒に歌ってもらおうかなと思って。
For the last one, I thought I'd have Fubuki sing with me.
あ、じゃあ邪魔しない程度に。
Ah, then I'll try not to get in the way.
合いの手をね、得意だって言ってるから。合いの手をお願いします。
She says she's good at backing chants. Please do the backing chants.
そうですね、合いの手を。程よい合いの手を。
That's right, chants. Just the right amount of chants.
うん。お願いします。
Yeah. Please do.
はい！
Okay!
というわけで皆さん、何を歌うんですか？
So, everyone, what am I going to sing?
ちょっとね、最後の曲になりますが、喜んでくれると嬉しいです。
It's the last song, and I hope you'll enjoy it.
ちょっと喉のあたりドキドキしますけれども。
My throat feels a bit nervous.
最後は、「夢見る空へ」で締めたいと思います。
For the finale, I'd like to close with "Yumemiru Sora e".
では。
Well then.
水がかり、ありがとう。
Thanks for the water.
ラストウォーター。
Last water.
センキュー、センキュー、センキュー。
Thank you, thank you, thank you.
えっと、はい。では「夢見る空へ」です。
Uh, yes. Here is "Yumemiru Sora e".
よろしくお願いします！
Please enjoy!
重ねた手はギュッと離さずに
Holding tight our joined hands, never letting go
行くよ
Here we go
夢見る空へ
Towards the dreaming sky
作詞・作曲・編曲：永塚健登
Towards the Dreaming Sky
Lyrics, Composition, Arrangement: Kento Nagatsuka
最後だけど、みんな盛り上がっていこう！
It's the last one, so let's get hyped, everyone!
窓越しに見上げた
Looking up through the window
とても小さな空
At a very tiny sky
ここで出会えたのは
What I encountered here
数え切れない奇跡
Are countless miracles
繰り返した一歩が
Each step repeated
きらめきを繋いで
Connects the sparkles
星のような笑顔導いた
Leading to a star-like smile
Step by day みんなの声が力になる
Step by day, everyone's voices become my strength
Step by stage ここでそれぞれ描くもの
Step by stage, what we each draw here
それぞれ目指すもの
What we each aim for
それぞれ願った夢
The dream each of us wished for
重ねた手はギュッと離さずに
Holding tight our joined hands, never letting go
一人一人違う色
Each and every person has a different color
輝き出す時めき
A sparkle that begins to shine
...そっと描く 真っ直ぐに
...softly drawing, straight ahead.
行くよ！ (行こう！)
Here I go! (Let's go!)
夢見る空へ
To the dreaming sky!
笑い合ったことや つきそうにない話題
The things we laughed about, and topics that didn't seem to fit.
思い出いっぱいなのに あっという間の日々
Even though they're full of memories, the days passed in a flash.
上書きじゃなくて 名前付けて保存
Not overwriting them, but saving them with a name.
どれも全部大事って 言いきれる
I can say for sure that every single one is important.
One for All みんなのためが力になる
One for All, being there for everyone becomes my strength.
All for One 今日も賑やかすぎるくらい
All for One, even today it's almost too lively.
笑顔が止まらない
The smiles don't stop.
思いは膨らんでいく
Our feelings keep on growing.
重ねた手はギュッと噛みしめた
I squeezed our joined hands tight.
一人一人違う声で 歌声は広がる
With each person's different voice, our singing spreads out.
風を感じたら 真っ直ぐに
Once you feel the breeze, go straight ahead.
行くよ！ (行こう！)
Here I go! (Let's go!)
夢見る空へ
To the dreaming sky!
憧れて手を伸ばし
Longing and reaching out,
掴み取った その光が
that light I finally grasped...
いつの日か また誰かの憧れに変わる
Will one day become someone else's longing again.
繋げよう
Let's connect them.
みんな今日は一杯ありがとう！
Thank you so much for today, everyone!
ちょっと失敗しちゃったところもあったけど
There were some parts where I messed up a bit, but...
このステージ、凄い楽しかったよ！ありがとうね！
this stage was so much fun! Thank you!
重ねた手はギュッと離さずに
Without letting go of our joined hands...
一人一人違う色で 描き出すときめき
Painting our excitement with each person's different color.
出会ったすべてにありがとう
Thank you for everything I've encountered.
奇跡だって起こせるんだ ずっとずっと傍にいるよ
We can even make miracles happen. I'll always be by your side.
行くよ！ (行こう！)
Here I go! (Let's go!)
夢見る空へ
To the dreaming sky!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
というわけで
And so...
以上、大神ミオ 2周年記念3Dライブでした！
That was Ookami Mio's 2nd Anniversary 3D Live!
ありがとうございました！
Thank you very much!
フブキングも合いの手ありがとうね！
Fubuki-ng, thank you for the backup calls too!
よ、よ、よ、よ！
Yo, yo, yo, yo!
助かったよー
It really helped~
いや、もう完全に心はミオファでしたね！
No, my heart was completely that of a Mio-fa (Mio's fan)!
もうフブキはね、デビュー当初から、この2年間ずっと一緒に歩いてきたから
Fubuki and I have walked together for these past two years, ever since my debut.
ね、ホントに！
Right, truly!
1周年記念の時も、マイクが…1周年記念の時も、一緒に放送出てくれたり
During the 1st anniversary, the mic... during the 1st anniversary too, you were on the broadcast with me.
そう、2周年も絶対一緒に出てほしいなって思って！
Yes, I really wanted you to be here for the 2nd anniversary too!
いや、ありがと！
No, thank you!
フブキが来てくれて、ホントに嬉しかったです！
I'm really glad Fubuki could come!
可愛いな、こちらこそだよ！
How cute, same here!
大好きミオんだぞ！
I love you, Mio-n!
よしよししてくれる？
Can you give me a "there, there"?
あ、ホントにいいの？私、空気だけで…
Oh, really? I'll just do the air...
あ、よしよし、ミオ、よしよし。お疲れさん。
...there, there, Mio, there, there. Good job.
テクニシャンなんだよな、ホント！
She's really a technician, seriously!
ミオのツボを心得てるんだよな
She knows exactly how to get to Mio.
というわけで
And so...
はい、ということでね、ライブは終わりなんですけど、ミオからの告知が、ある？
Yes, so the live is over, but does Mio have an announcement?
ザワザワ…皆さん、ちょっと前から言ってたんですけどね
*Murmuring*... Everyone, I've been mentioning this for a little while now.
あのですね、皆さん、なんと、2周年記念ボイス発売されます！
Well, everyone, guess what? 2nd Anniversary voices will be on sale!
出たー！イエーイ！
It's here! Yay!
え、ボイスだけなんですか？
Eh, just voices?
ちょっとあの…2周年記念ボイスに、特典というほど…でも凄く、特典というにはおこがましいのではないかというくらい、凄く沢山、あの、グッズを作っていただきまして
Well... with the 2nd anniversary voices, there are bonuses... well, it might be presumptuous to even call them bonuses, but they've made a lot of goods for me.
グッズセットなども、ご用意させていただいております！
We also have goods sets and more prepared!
活動二周年記念 12/7(月)より販売
ボイス＆グッズ全部セット
2nd Anniversary Celebration - On sale from 12/7 (Mon)
Voice & Goods Complete Set
なにー！あー！
What! Ahhh!
なんだこれはミオ！
What is this, Mio?!
これ、あの、ちょっと恥ずかしいんですけど
This, um, it's a bit embarrassing, but...
ミオ、ミオ、ミオ、はい、はい、はい
Mio, Mio, Mio, yes, yes, yes.
結婚するのか、俺以外の奴と！
Are you getting married?! To someone other than me?!
バカタレ！なんだこの、嫁ミオ！
You idiot! What is this, Bride Mio?!
許さんぞ白上！
I won't forgive you, Shirakami!
ちょっとあの、嫁ミオ…ですじゃないですけど
It's, um, not exactly Bride Mio, but...
今回は
And this time...
泉彩パパがなんと描き下ろしで、こちらのイラストを書いていただきました！
Izumi Sai-papa has drawn this illustration especially for us!
イェーイ！
Yay!
内容が描き下ろしキャンバスアートって何ですか？
What is this "Newly drawn canvas art"?
そうなんです、この描き下ろしイラストのキャンバスアートが
That's right, this newly drawn illustration is available as canvas art.
ボイスのグッズセットで付いてきます。
It comes with the voice & goods set.
なるほど！その下はミオがいつも見てるお守り！？
I see! And the next one is the "Omamori" that Mio always looks at?
そうなんです。実はですね、うちがお守りが欲しいなと思いまして、
Well, actually, I wanted an omamori for myself...
それで、うちのお守りを、ミオのお守りを作りました。
so I made one. Mio's omamori.
なんだってー！お守り！？
What! An omamori!?
そうなんですよ。あとはハンドタオルですね。
Yes. And then there's the hand towel.
え、待って「ミオファの証」ってある！証なの！？
Wait, it says "Proof of Miofa"! Is it a proof!?
まあ、ちょっとミオファっぽいデザインにしたのよ。
Well, I made the design feel like something a Miofa would have.
デザインもうちが1から手掛けまして。
I worked on the design from scratch.
本当に！？すごい！すごいシンプルなんだけど...
Really! Amazing! It's so simple though...
こんなのだったらみんな持ち歩ける、あ、これこれこれ！
I thought people could carry it around easily... oh, there it is!
本当だ！え、めっちゃ可愛いよ！みんな出てる！
Ah, it's true! It's so cute! They're all on the screen!
こんなんだったら可愛いかなと思って作ったデザインと、
I thought this would be cute, so I designed it like this.
ミオファの証ハンドタオル可愛い！結構シンプルだね。
The Proof of Miofa hand towel is cute! It's quite simple.
そうなんです。さらに「ミオと一緒にお出かけキーホルダー」という事で、
Yes. And next is the "Out on a date with Mio Key Holder"...
SNS風キーホルダーって知ってる？
Do you know about SNS-style key holders?
知ってる知ってる！これであれだよね、背景とかやって撮るやつだよね！
I know them! You can take photos with it in the background!
さすが！よくご存知で！
Exactly! You're so knowledgeable!
ミオと一緒にお出かけデートキーホルダーじゃん！
So it's a date key holder with Mio!
デート...まあ...
A date... well...
許さん！そしてもっと出た、これはビッグゴッドさん！？
I won't allow it! Oh! Next is... Big God-san?
そうなんです、オリジナルタロットと申しますが、
Yes, "Original Tarot Cards".
今回3枚だけなんですよ。大アルカナ何枚だと思って...
But there's only 3 cards this time. Guess how many Major Arcana there are...
ビッグゴッドミオさん、大アルカナ何枚ありました？
Big God Mio-san, how many are there?
全部で21枚。
21 cards in total.
これ3枚ずつしか出ないんですか？何年かかりますかこれ！？
So only 3 cards are coming out? How many years will it take to collect them all!?
そうですね、10年後に全てが揃うという計算となっております。
At this rate, it'll take 10 years to get the full set.
どこかのマンスリー何とかみたいに！？
Like one of those monthly collectible magazines!?
まあ、シリーズ化じゃないですけど、1年に1回は少なすぎだから、
Well, I want to make it a series. Once a year is too slow,
3ヶ月に1回のペースとかね、どっかでドカーンと枚数出したりね。
so maybe every 3 months or so? Or maybe I'll release a bunch at once later.
タロット欲しい！
I want the tarot cards!
実は今回の3枚で右側にあるタイガーをなつかせてるやつとかあるんで。
And one of the 3 cards this time is the one where I'm taming a tiger.
タイガー！「力」のカードね！パワーを感じます！
A tiger! "The Strength" card! I feel the power!
ちなみに、ボイスってどんなのなんだい？
By the way, what kind of voice pack is it?
気になるでしょ。
I'm curious!
コソコソなんか台本みたいなのやってるなと思ってたミオーン！
I saw Mio whispering something into a script!
ボイスちょっと気になりますよ、だってキャンバスアートがこれですよ！
I'm curious about the voice, because look at this canvas art!
今回、ウェディングボイスってやつを撮っちゃいまして。
Well, this time I recorded a "Wedding Voice" pack.
ウ、ウェ、ウェウェウェ！？ちょっとちょっと！
W-W-Wedding!? Hold on a minute!
多分それでパパがこんなイラスト書いてくれたんだと思うけど。
That's probably why Papa drew this illustration.
ウェディング！？ウェディングボイス！？
Wedding!? Wedding voice!?
結婚するのかー！
Are you getting married!?
うわあああああ！ミオー！白上のだー！
Nooooo! Mio! You're a bride!?
というわけで、皆さんよかったらうちと結婚してください！
So, please marry me everyone!
泣かないで！泣かないで！
Don't cry! Don't cry!
こちらのボイスとグッズ、全部をセットで買ってくれた方には、
And for those who buy the full set of voice & goods,
特典として、もう1個のやつを...
there's a special bonus...
お、出ますかね？何が出るんだ？
Oh, is it coming up? What is it?
はい！なんと泉彩パパが差分で、笑顔のミオも書いてくれたので！
Izumi Sai-papa drew a variation with a smiling face!
これをポストカードにさせていただいて、うちに直筆のサインを...
This will be a postcard with my hand-signed message.
メッセージとかも書いてお送りしようかなと思ってます！
I'll write a message and send it out!
あの、誰に向けた笑顔なのそれ！？ミオー！
Wait, who is that smile for!? Mio!
「うちとつぐね」みたいな、「結婚してくれてありがとう」みたいな。
It's like "Let's get married" or "Thank you for marrying me."
うちもまだ結婚したことないからさ、感情的なものは分からないんだけど、
I've never been married, so I don't really know the feelings,
でもなんか凄く嬉しそうだね。
but she looks very happy.
これいつから購入できるんですか！？負けたくない！
When can I buy this!? I don't want to lose!
買うためにも...
In order to buy it...
時間を教えてくれねーか！？
Can you tell us the time!?
実は直筆サイン戦争、今回無いんです。
Actually, there's no handwritten signature war this time.
え、本当に？
Wait, really?
買えばもらえる？
You get it if you buy it?
応募者全員サービス。
It's available for all applicants.
やったぜ、みんな！
We did it, everyone!
落ちるぞ、今！
I'm tearing up right now!
ミオファの森は平和でないといけないなと思って。
I thought the Mio-fa forest should be peaceful.
やったー！ ありがとう！
Yay! Thank you!
良かったみんな、数量限定じゃないぞ。
I'm so glad, everyone. It's not limited quantity.
で、いつからですか？ こちらは。
So, when does it start? This one.
一応、本日、
Well, it's today,
本日の10時半から...
From 10:30 today...
10時半から！ お、もうすぐだ。
From 10:30! Oh, that's soon.
なので、はい。なのでちょっと...
So, yes. So for a moment...
URLなどもTwitterなどで、はい。
The URL will be on Twitter and such, yes.
お、告知されてたかな？
Oh, has it been announced?
あ、なんか放送の概要欄に。
Ah, it seems it's in the stream description.
あ、もう出てるかな？
Ah, is it already there?
もう貼ってくれてますね。
It's already been posted.
でも購入できるのは10時半から。
But you can only purchase it from 10:30.
あ、そうです、そうです。
Ah, that's right, that's right.
ゲートは開いてるんですけど、
購入は10時半からとなっております。
The gate is open, but
purchase starts from 10:30.
なるほど。
I see.
ちょっとすいません、あのパネルの方、
もう一度見せてもらっていいですか？
Excuse me, could you show
that panel once more?
嫁ミオのパネルの方のイラストを、
ちょっといいですか？
Could I see the illustration on the
"Bride Mio" panel again?
ちょっと恥ずかしいけど。
It's a bit embarrassing though.
グッズ詳細じゃない方の、1枚目のやつを、
もう一度出してもらっていいですか？
Could you put up the first one again,
the one without the details?
この顔！
This face!
ねえ。
I know, right.
この顔、おかあさんにこはズルいじゃん！
This "Mom Smile" face is totally unfair!
え、しかもさ、下で結んでるね、ミオ。
And look, your hair is tied down, Mio.
いやそうなんだよ。珍しい髪型でしょ。
Yeah, that's right. It's a rare hairstyle, isn't it?
そうそうそう。
Yes, exactly.
いつもはぴょんぴょん跳ねてるけどさ、
なんかショートっぽい感じがしていい、この髪型。
It's usually all bouncy, but this short-ish
look is really nice.
そうなんだよ、可愛いよね。
ちょっと大人っぽい髪型さ。
I know, it's cute. A bit of a mature hairstyle.
下結びとかどう、白上、オークションにしないかい？
How about this hair-tied style? Shirakami,
should we put it up for auction?
これね。
This one, right.
この髪型も、可愛いめっちゃ。
This hairstyle is also super cute.
ありがとう。
Thank you.
良かったみんな。戦争無いのでね、ぜひとも。
I'm glad, everyone. Since there's no war,
please do get it.
平和です。平和ですけど...
It's peaceful. It's peaceful, but...
ミオは渡さんから白上を倒してから取りに来い！
I won't give Mio away, so defeat
Shirakami before you come for her!
白上を倒さなきゃいけないらしいので皆さん頑張ってください。
Apparently you have to defeat Shirakami,
so everyone, good luck.
フブラになるぞ！
I'll be like a final boss!
というわけで、皆さん、本当に今日は、集まってくださり。
Anyway, everyone, thank you so much
for gathering today.
そして最後まで見てくださり、本当にありがとうございました。
And thank you so much for
watching until the end.
フブキも最後まで見守り、どうもありがとう。
And Fubuki, thank you for watching
over me until the end.
あ、ちょっと白上から一個いいかい？
Ah, can I say one thing from Shirakami?
なんだい？
What is it?
コメント欄のみんなとやりたいことがある。
There's something I want to do with
everyone in the comments.
何だ？
What?
じゃあ、準備いいか？ 白上と同じ文章を打ってね。行くよ？
Alright, ready? Type the same
sentence as Shirakami. Here we go.
ミオ、2周年おめでとうー！
Mio, happy 2nd anniversary!
あー、ありがとうー！
Ah, thank you!
イェーイ！ ありがとうー！
Yay! Thank you!
ちょっと時差があるから、コメント来るかな？
There's a bit of a delay, I wonder if the comments will come?
コメントバーっと見て終わりたい。
I want to see the comments flood in and then end.
ありがとうー！
Thank you!
2周年おめでとうのコメントを見ながら
幸せな気持ちで終わりたいと思います。
I'd like to end with a happy feeling
while looking at your anniversary comments.
皆さん、本当に今日はどうもありがとうございました。
Everyone, thank you so much for today.
また何かしらの形でリベンジさせてください。お願いします。
Please let me have a revenge match
in some form. I'm counting on you.
おつミオー！ ありがとね！
Otsu-Mio! Thanks everyone!
バイバーイ！
Bye-bye!